Resume



Khaliqur Rahman Wahidi

113, 6th Floor, Alif Apt. Near Congress Bhawan, Ellisbridge, Ahmadabad – 380 006 Contact No. 9998945232 / 079 30422820 Email: khaliquesys@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Initiative, high task orientated temperament for team work and leading the team. To make optimal use of theoretical / Practical knowledge, experience and exposure gained in a fiercely competitive market where my knowledge, skills and experience are put to a maximum use, encouraging personal and professional growth.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:

A qualified Professional having 16 plus years of experience in Operational Management, HR Consultancy, CRM and Sales Coordination with National, International Organization and Government bodies The areas of expertise are in the field of Operations, Administration, Purchasing, Procurement, Training, Sales, IT Support and Documentation & Asset of Records.

AREAS OF EXPERTISATION:

- Deployment of NEEM (National Employability Enhance Mission) Scheme.
- Prepare proposal for the affiliation from VTP / NCVT / NSDC bodies and follow up.
- Planned and Executed Government Educational Projects like DDU-GKY, PMVKY and NDLM programs.
- Conduct Seminars on the Skill Gap Analysis.
- Interview / Hire and Training the candidates for suitable posts.
- University / Colleges / Schools and Institute connect.
- Undertake Brand and Promotional activities.
- Coordination with Private / Public and Government sectors.
- Ability to work independently and to complete the assigned task within the given parameters of instructions.
- Ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines with positive approach and attitude.
- Strong organizational skill with excellent Communication / Presentation and time Management.
- Strong analytical skill with people management and change management.
- Having good HR related knowledge.
- Focus on facts and details.
- Most important is clear communication in management.
- Training under team and sound decision maker.
- Overall co-ordination of manpower planning, and ensuring cultural fit.
- Bulk hiring i.e. recruitment specialist for Industries like Tata Nano, Reliance Industries and Pharmaceutical companies. Also recruit for Maruti Suzuki.
- Expertise in handling Compensation & Benefits, Implementing Policies, Operations, back-office operations and setting process with key focus on top line profitability.
- Management of Mediclaim / Accidental Insurance / Life Insurance policies and administration.

- Have Ability to handle administrative tasks in co-ordination with respective Departments.
- Monthly Statutory compliance audit of Vendors for Contract Labour Act, Minimum Wages Act- payment made as per schedule employment, PF Act, ESIC Act Conduct Quarterly Audit of Principle Employer under PF Act, ESIC Act, Employment Exchange Act, Maharashtra Labor Welfare Fund, Payment of Bonus Act, Maternity Benefit Act
- Visa (Transit / Visit / Employment):
- To monitor and initiate appropriate actions for the execution of requests related to new visa applications.
- Family / relative visa, visa / passport renewals, visa cancellations and new business visas / permits.
- Passport control for employees Renewal of employment visa process.
- Apply visa for the corporate guests and the executive.

Industry Experience:

⇒ AS Info Solutions (Vapi) Position: Regional Head

Sep 2019 - Till Date

- Responsible for overall performance of assigned region.
- Answerable for operational issues from clients.
- Assist in monitoring overall customer satisfaction.
- Maintain communication with all clients and liaise for long pending payments to regularize the payment system of the company at regional level.
- Analyze the performance and provide feedback, guidance, training and encouragement in order to impact results.
- Assist in the developing of new operations procedures and policies.
- Assist training department with new franchisees and ongoing training.
- Conduct and attend regional meetings for assigned regions.
- Ability to Analyze and think strategically · Attention to Detail · People skills

⇒ Yashaswi Academy for Skills (Ahmedabad) Position: Operations Head

Oct 2016 - Sep 2019

- Hands on experience in handling PAN Gujarat Operations for NEEM (National Employability Enhance Mission). An initiative of our Hon'ble PM Skilling India.
- Good connects with Industries and Govt bodies across Gujarat.
- Recruitment / Planning / Deployment and execution of Scheme.
- Serving prestigious Clients like Tata Motors Ltd. (Sanand) / Asahi India Glass / Sun Pharmaceuticals to name a few.
- Under NEEM Scheme around 4000 plus NEEM Trainees in various locations of Gujarat under my supervision.
- Liaising with Local and Govt Officials.
- Extensive Travelling as and when required as per projects need. (Including Outstates).
- Administrative Transport / Canteen and Medical facilities on urgent in case of emergency for the trainees.
- Induction and training.

⇒ Platinum Construction (Edu Div) Ahmadabad Position: Centre Manager

Feb 2015 - Sep 2016

- Hands on experience in Indian Governments Educational projects like, PMVKY, NDLM and DDU-GKY. That is skill gap program.
- Meeting with School, Colleges, Institution, and Corporate for future business prospect.
- Managing and Coordinating seminars on for IT, Non IT, PMP, Soft skills.
- Know how to implement market strategy to get effective business in existing market.
- Use tools and techniques to update the market view and many more.
- A complete knowledge of Strategy Planning and churn management.

⇒ NIIT (Vedang Innovation) Franchisee

Nov 2013 - Jan 2015

Position: Business Manager

- Handle all marketing and promotional activities for the company.
- Conducting seminar in Schools / Colleges and University on latest topics.
- Coordinating with other respective heads to achieve the target.
- Meeting with School, Colleges, Institution, and Corporate for future business prospect.
- Managing and Coordinating seminars on for IT, Non IT, PMP, Soft skills.
- Use and implement market strategy to get effective business in existing market.
- Forecasting monthly business plan for the company.

⇒ Xtrakeen Interactive (Ahmadabad) Position: Business Head

Oct 2011 - Oct 2013

- Conducting & Coordinating for IT, Non IT, PMP, Soft skills and Toastmasters. The training delivered by world class certified Instructors from different countries like UK / USA.
- Organized and conducted much financial and sales training.
- To get business for the company.

⇒ Karimah Trading & Contracting Establishment, (KSA) Position: Manager Training

Nov 2009 - Nov 2011

- Coordinated with Ministry's like MODA, MOE and MOH ongoing and upcoming projects.
- Coordinating with other respective heads within the Organization and the clients.
- Organized, Conducted, Coordinated and Scheduled IT and Management Training Programs including PMP training programs.
- Attended many Seminars on IT and Management Training Programs.
- Preparing Annual Company's Training Calendar and Training budget.
- Control and coordinate activities related to training with in the limited span of time and to save Company expenses.

⇒ Sysorex Arabia LLC (Part of Sysorex Federal Inc. USA) Position: IT Support & Training Coordinator

Nov 2006 - Nov 2009

- Managing / Organizing & Coordinating for IT, Non IT, PMP, Soft skills and Toastmasters. The training delivered by world class certified Instructors from different countries like UK / USA.
- Coordinate with Administration Department to ensure the Training and Development of Employees.
- Follow up on Annual Training Budget.
- Manages grievance procedures (Deduction, Salary, Visa etc.) and Prepare Annual Training Calendar / Preparing Daily progress reports.
- Control and coordinate activities related to petty cash purchase materials and timely reimbursement claim.

⇒ K. T. C. Est. (PCL Sub Contractor) Riyadh (K.S.A.) Position: Projects Coordinator

Nov 2003 - Aug 2006

- Project Coordinator at School Project Al Baha Region (KSA).
- Project value 15 Million Saudi Riyals.
- Responsibilities includes, coordinate with Ministry's Consultant,
- Taking material approval, design / drawing approval,
- Taking Proposed Drawing approval.
- Preparing Weekly / Monthly Progress Report.
- Making Invoices as per Ministry Performa.

Educational Qualifications:

- ⇒ B. A. With Computer Application from Jamia Millia Islamia (A Central University) 2002 New Delhi.
- ⇒ Senior Secondary School Certificate from Jamia Millia Islamia (A Central University) 1998 New Delhi.
- ⇒ Higher Secondary School Examination from Gandhi Inter College Sikanderpur Ballia (UP Board Allahabad) 1995.

Computer Skills:

Application Software: MS Office – (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Internet, MS Outlook, Email

Platform (O/S): Windows 2000 server, professional and workstation. Widows ME, Windows XP,

Windows vista & Windows 7

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 08/08/1979 **Marital Status:** Married

Driving License: Indian as well as Valid Saudi License too.

Sex: Male

Languages Known: English / Hindi / Urdu / Arabic (Read / Write & Speak)

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is complete and true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I would truly prove myself and would sincerely serve my best for the growth of the organization.